Register of the Trotsky collection, 1917-1995
Hoover Institution Archives
- DEWEY COMMISSION FILE, 1936-1938. (Box 25-26)
  Correspondence, bulletins, reports, serial issues, minutes, press releases, broadsides, depositions, and exhibits, generated by the American Committee for the Defense of Leon Trotsky, and by the Commission of Inquiry into the Charges Made against Leon Trotsky in the Moscow Trials, chaired by John Dewey, which held hearings in Mexico City in 1937. Does not include writings by or correspondence of Trotsky. Arranged by physical form. See also SUBJECT FILE/Commission of Inquiry into the Charges Made against Leon Trotsky in the Moscow Trials; and SUBJECT FILE/Moscow Trials, Moscow, R.S.F.S.R., 1936-1937
  - General
    - Broadsides, appeals, declaration of principles of the American Committee for the Defense of Leon Trotsky, and press release, resolutions, and messages of support from mass meeting in New York City, 1936. (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - 1937
      - January-March. Letters, press releases, minutes, and broadsides. Includes copies of letters by Charles A. Beard, Paul F. Brissenden, Lewis Browne, Mauritz A. Hallgren, Sidney Howard, George Novack, Edward Alsworth Ross, Meyer Schapiro, and Norman Thomas; draft of procedures for Commission of Inquiry into the Charges Made against Leon Trotsky in the Moscow Trials; pamphlet by Hallgren, Why I Resigned from the Trotsky Defense Committee; statement by John Chamberlain and James T. Farrell; statement by Ligue des Droits de l'Homme; speech by John Dewey; and typescript on Kleber Legay (Folder 5)
      - April. Letters, press releases, statements, minutes, and reports. Includes copies of letters by Carleton Beals, Louis Hacker and Felix Morrow; and statements by Beals and John Dewey (Folder 6)
      - May. Press releases, broadside, speeches, report, and letter. Includes report on the work of the American Committee for the Defense of Leon Trotsky by George Novack and Felix Morrow; speeches by John Dewey, Suzanne LaFollette and Benjamin Stolberg; and letter by Jan Frankel (Folder 7)
      - Press releases, broadsides, and statement. Includes letters by John Dewey, George Novack, Jean van Heijenoort, and John G. Wright; and statement by Dewey, June-December. (Folder 8)
    - 1938. Press releases, letters, and speeches. Includes letter by Corliss Lamont; copies of letters by Horace M. Kallen, George Novack and Norman Thomas; mimeograph copy of Sidney Hook, "Corliss Lamont, Friend of the G.P.U."; report on the work of the American Committee for the Defense of Leon Trotsky; speech by Suzanne LaFollette; and special issue of Biulleten' oppozitsii (Folder 9)
  - Background material, Printed matter and typed copies of documents assembled as exhibits or as background material for testimony at the hearings of the Commission of Inquiry into the Charges Made against Leon Trotsky in the Moscow Trials, Mexico City; depositions by Pierre Frank, Henri Molinier, Arven Tarov and others; and bulletin issue of a Labour and Socialist International commission of inquiry, 1937. (Folder 10)
  - Bulletins, 1937
    - American Committee for the Defense of Leon Trotsky. News Bulletin. No. (1937 January 23-May 3), 1-6 (Folder 11)
    - British Committee for the Defence of Leon Trotsky. Information Bulletin. No. 2, (1937 July) (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Comite pour l'Enquete sur le Proces de Moscou (France). Bulletin mensuel d'information et de presse, (1937 January) (Folder 2)
  - Newspaper issues, 1937-1938
    - Socialist Appeal offprint, "An Open Letter to the Members of the Communist Party", (1938 March 19) (Folder 3)
    - Truth about the Moscow Trials. No. 1, (1937 April) (Folder 4)
  - Report, 1937. Commission of Inquiry into the Charges Made against Leon Trotsky in the Moscow Trials, Abstract of the Final Report, (mimeograph and printed copies) (Folder 5)
- NATALIIA SEDOVA TROTSKAIA FILE, 1935-1961. (Box 26-27)
  Correspondence of and writings by Nataliia Sedova Trotskaia (1882-1962), wife of Leon Trotsky. Arranged by physical form. See also SUBJECT FILE/Trotskaia, Nataliia Sedova
  - Correspondence, 1935-1960
    - Berger, Iosif, Relates to Sergei Sedov, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Bleecker, Sylvia, 1948-1960 (Folder 7)
    - Cannon, James P., 1940-1945 (Folder 8)
    - Cardenas, Lazaro, 1940 (Folder 9)
    - Curtis Brown Ltd., 1949 (Folder 10)
    - De Silver, Margaret, 1943 (Folder 11)
    - Dunayevskaya, Raya, 1942-1946 (Folder 12)
    - Fourth International, 1951 (Folder 13)
    - Frankel, Jan, 1937-1938 (Folder 14)
    - Goldman, Albert, 1941-1946 (Folder 15)
    - Gordon, Sam, 1948 (Folder 16)
    - Hansen, Joseph, 1941 (Folder 17)
    - Harvard University, 1958-1959 (Folder 18)
    - Held, Walter, 1940 (Folder 19)
    - Kommunisticheskaia Partiia Sovetskogo Soiuza, 1956 (Folder 20)
    - Martin, Jeanne
      - 1938 February-April (Folder 21)
      - 1938 May-1939 (Folder 22)
    - Morrow, Felix, 1941 (Folder 23)
    - Pioneer Press, 1957 (Folder 24)
    - Shachtman, Max, 1959 (Folder 25)
    - Simon and Schuster (Publishers), 1949 (Folder 26)
    - Socialist Workers Party, 1940-1949 (Folder 27)
    - Stein, Morris, 1948 (Folder 28)
    - Van Heijenoort, Jean, 1959 (Folder 29)
    - Voroshilov, Kliment, 1956 (Folder 30)
    - Weber, Jack, 1944-1952 (Folder 31)
    - Weber, Sara
      - 1935-1946 June (Folder 32)
      - 1946 July-1948 (Folder 33)
      - 1949 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - 1950-1951 (Folder 2)
      - 1952-1954 (Folder 3)
      - 1955-1956 (Folder 4)
      - 1957-1960 (Folder 5)
    - Wright, John G., 1941-1946 (Folder 6)
    - Yamanishi, E., 1949 (Folder 7)
  - Writings, 1937-1961
    - Will, Typescripts (in Russian, French and English) (Folder 8)
    - "To the Conscience of the Entire World!" Relates to Sergei Sedov. Mimeograph copy (in English), 1937 February 6. (Folder 9)
    - Statement regarding Diego Rivera, Typescript (in French), 1939. (Folder 10)
    - "Otets i syn," Typescript with handwritten additions (in Russian), 1940 June 8. (Folder 11)
    - "Tak eto bylo," 1940 November. Relates to the assassination of Leon Trotsky. Published in Leon Trotsky: The Man and His Work (New York, Typescript with handwritten additions (in Russian), and typescript (in English), 1969). (Folder 12)
    - Memoir of Leon Trotsky, ca. 1940-1943
      - Typescript with handwritten additions (in Russian) (Folder 13)
      - Typescript with handwritten additions (in English) (Folder 14)
    - "Kto zashchishchaet terroristov?" Holograph (in Russian), 1941. (Folder 15)
    - "Vinovnost' Stalina," Typescript with handwritten additions (in Russian), 1942 April 18. (Folder 16)
    - "Forgery of Trotsky's Will," Typescript (in English), 1948 April. (Folder 17)
    - Radio Liberation broadcast to the Soviet Union, Typed transcript (in English), 1956. (Folder 18)
    - "A Page to the Diary," 1958 July. Relates to the introduction by Max Shachtman to Trotsky's Diary in Exile, 1935 (Cambridge, Mass., Typescript (in English) and typescript (incomplete, in Russian) (Folder 19)
    - Letter to the editor, France-Soir, Typescript (in English), 1961 November 9. (Folder 20)
- LEV SEDOV FILE, 1936-1938. (Box 28)
  Correspondence of and writings by Lev Sedov (1906-1938), son of Leon Trotsky. Arranged by physical form. See also SUBJECT FILE/Sedov, Lev
  - Correspondence, 1937-1938
    - Trotskaia, Nataliia Sedova, 1937 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified, 1938 (Folder 2)
    - Wolf, Erwin, 1937 (Folder 3)
  - Writings, 1936-1938
    - "K voprosu o semichasovom rabochem dne v SSSR," Biulleten' oppozitsii, Typescript with handwritten additions (in Russian), 1936 January. (Folder 4)
    - "Stakhanovskoe dvizhenie," Biulleten' oppozitsii, Typescript with handwritten additions (in Russian), 1936 January. (Folder 5)
    - "Moscow Trials," Holograph copy (in English), 1937 January 5. (Folder 6)
    - "Vyshinskii protiv Vyshinskii," Biulleten' oppozitsii, Typescript (in Russian), 1937 March. (Folder 7)
    - Will, Photocopy of holograph (in French) and typed copy (in French), 1938 February 9. (Folder 8)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1920-1980 (Box 28-33)
  Letters, writings, memoranda, internal bulletins, clippings, printed articles, and serial issues, relating to Leon Trotsky and associated topics. For the most part, material collected by the Socialist Workers Party and the Library of Social History. Does not include writings by or correspondence of Trotsky. Arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - Commission of Inquiry into the Charges Made against Leon Trotsky in the Moscow Trials. Newspaper and journal articles from The Daily Worker, Modern Monthly, New Masses, The New Republic, The New York Herald-Tribune, The New York Times and other publications,; printed copy of Alan Wald, "Memories of the John Dewey Commission: Forty Years Later," 1977; and notes. See also Moscow Trials, Moscow, R.S.F.S.R., 1936-1937., 1936-1938 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Communism. Printed copies of three pamphlets: Herman Gorter, Het Imperialisme, de Wereldoorlog en de Social-Democratie (Amsterdam, 1920); Herman Gorter, Het Opportunisme in de Nederlandsche Communistische Partij (Amsterdam, 1921); and V. I. Lenin, Staat en Revolutie (Dutch translation by Herman Gorter, Amsterdam (Folder 10)
  - Espionage, Soviet. Clippings,; printed copies of articles by Walter Krivitsky, 1939; and photocopies of holograph notes written by Krivitsky prior to his ostensible suicide, 1941, 1937-1956 (Folder 11)
  - Held, Walter. Typescript biographical sketch, 1977 (Folder 12)
  - Miscellany
    - Clippings, broadside, note, and letter, 1937-1972 (Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous bulletin issues of the International Left Opposition and International Communist League. Includes: Bulletin de la Gauche (Opposition), No. 5-7 (1932 August 24-October 15); Biulleten' oppozitsii, No. 32 (1932 December); Bulletin international des Jeunesses Bolcheviks-Leninistes, No. 2 (1934 August); and Bulletin interieur international, No. 4, (1938 June) (Folder 14)
  - Moscow Trials, Moscow, R.S.F.S.R., See also Commission of Inquiry into the Charges Made against Leon Trotsky in the Moscow Trials, 1936-1937.
    - General. Serial issues of Common Sense, Controversy, Foreign Policy Bulletin, International Review, Modern Monthly, Moscow News, and Soviet Russia Today,; mimeograph copy of Eugene Lyons, "The Terror in Stalin's Russia: An Open Letter to Upton Sinclair," 1938; and typescript statement by H. G. Wells, Arthur Koestler and others, "Nuremberg and the Moscow Trials," ca. 1945, 1937-1938 (Folder 15)
    - Clippings. Includes articles from The Daily Worker, The Nation, New Masses, The New Republic, The New York Post, The New York Times, La Revolution proletarienne, Time, and Der Tog, 1934-1939 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Partisan Review. Clipping, n.d., and printed copy of Alan Wald, "Revolutionary Intellectuals: Partisan Review in the " 1974, 1930s (Folder 2)
  - Rivera, Diego. Clippings, 1951-1976 (Folder 3)
  - Salus, Wolfgang Vaclav. Typewritten biographical sketch, 1953 (Folder 4)
  - Sedov, Lev
    - General. Printed article,; mimeograph copy of eulogy for Sedov at New York City memorial meeting, 1938; bibliography of writings by Sedov; and typewritten memoir by Liliia Estrina, "Leon Sedov," 1975, 1937 (Folder 5)
    - Clippings. Obituaries and articles regarding circumstances of death, 1938 (Folder 6)
    - Memorial issues of newspapers and journals. Includes issues of Biulleten' oppozitsii, The Challenge of Youth, Cuarta Internacional, Der Einzige Weg, Inicial, La Lutte ouvriere, Oktober, Quatrieme Internationale, Revolution, Socialist Appeal, Unser Wort, and Workers' Voice, 1938 (Folder 7)
  - Sedov, Sergei. Printed statement by Iosif Berger, and fragment of typescript by P. Richards (Folder 8)
  - Soviet Union--Politics and government
    - Five typescript articles by Left Oppositionists: Lapin, "Kritika proekta programmy Kominterna,"; Khristian Rakovskii, "Politika rukovodstva i partiinyi rezhim," n.d.; "Nastroeniia molodezhi: Pis'mo iz Leningrada," 1932 (author unknown); Ante Ciliga, "V bor'be za vyezd iz SSSR," 1936; and F. Raskol'nikov, "Otkrytoe pis'mo Stalinu," 1939 (Folder 9)
    - Untitled typescript memoir (in Russian) by unidentified Russian Left Oppositionist, n.d., relating to experiences in the Russian Civil War and in the Left Opposition in the Soviet Union from, 1918 to 1941 (Folder 10)
  - Spain--History--Civil War, 1936-1939. Typescripts of Felix Giordano, "The Spanish Revolution and the Tasks of the International Proletariat," "The May Events in Catalonia" (author unknown), Charles Orr, "Report on the Situation of International Aid for the Spanish Revolution," and George M. Whiteside, " Appeal Resolution on Spain Straddles the Barricades"; mimeograph copies of Salemme-Joerger Group, "Shall the International Proletariat Give Material Aid to the Spanish Loyalist Government?", Marxist Policy Committee, "Against the Capitulators! No Aid to the People's Front! For a Marxist Policy on the Civil War in Spain!", and Marxist Policy Committee, "The Civil War in Spain and the SPUSA"; and broadsides by the Revolutionary Workers League (U.S.) and by the International Communist League Spanish Section; all, 1937 (Folder 11)
  - Stalin, Joseph. Printed articles by Louis Fischer, 1948, and clippings, 1938-1974 (Folder 12)
  - Strikes and lockouts--Drama. Typescript of play by Robert Sheldon Harte, "Strike Scenes: Four Scenes of the Opentown Strike of '39,", ca. 1939-1940 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Trials (Political crimes and offenses)--Soviet Union. Special issue of International Press Correspondence on trial of the "Industrial Party," 1930. See also Moscow Trials, Moscow, R.S.F.S.R., 1936-1937 (Folder 2)
  - Trotskaia, Nataliia Sedova. Letters exchanged between associates of Nataliia Sedova Trotskaia, and clippings, Includes letters by Sylvia Bleecker, Albert Goldman, Walter O'Rourke, and Esteban Volkov; and letters and memoranda relating to the deposit of Sara Weber's correspondence with Trotskaia in the Internationaal Instituut voor Sociale Geschiedenis. Does not include correspondence of Trotskaia, 1941-1975. (Folder 3)
  - Trotsky, Leon
    - General
      - Clippings
        - 1924-1940. Includes articles from The Daily Worker, Forward, The New Leader, The New York Times, Paris-Soir, Der Tog, and La Verite (Folder 4)
        - 1941-1979. Includes articles from Algemeen Dagblad, The Ceylon Daily News, The Ceylon Observer, Excelsior, Le Figaro, The Jerusalem Post, El Mercurio, Le Monde, The Nation, Neue Zurcher Zeitung, The New Statesman, The New York Herald-Tribune, The New York Times, New Zealand Truth, The Observer, Soviet Weekly, The Times of Ceylon, and Vrij Nederland (Folder 5)
      - Miscellany. Letters, leaflet, press release, news dispatch, notes, and sketch, 1932-1973 (Folder 6)
      - Printed articles
        - 1922-1940. Includes articles by James Burnham, Max Eastman, R. Pero, and George Bernard Shaw, and articles in Life, Time, and Todo (Folder 7)
        - 1940. Special commemorative issue of Claridad (Folder 8)
        - 1948-1967. Includes articles in Le Contrat social, Esquire, Queen's Quarterly, Socialist Standard, and Les Temps modernes (Folder 9)
        - 1971-1977. Includes articles in Les Lettres nouvelles, Matin, Proceso, and Sunday Times Magazine (London) (Folder 10)
      - Recollections by others
        - General. Printed articles, including articles by Arne Swabeck, Esteban Volkov, and Sara Weber, 1970-1977 (Box 31, Folder 1)
        - Hansen, Joseph, "With Trotsky to the End," Typescript (in Russian), 1969. (Folder 2)
        - Merlon, C., "A Reply to Eastman," Typescript (in English). Includes typed copy of response by Max Eastman, 1959. (Folder 3)
        - Robins, Harold, "Recollections," Typescript (in English), ca. 1950. (Folder 4)
        - Zeller, Fred, "Reminiscences of Leon Trotsky," Typed copy (in English), 1947. (Folder 5)
      - Typewritten articles
        - Untitled writing by unknown author, (in Russian); and Fernandez, Octavio, "Como se obtuvo el derecho de asilo para Leon Trotsky en Mexico," 1945 (in Spanish), ca. 1940-1941 (Folder 6)
        - De Silva, Ray, "Leon Trotsky: The Story of His Life," (in English), 1950 (Folder 7)
    - Archives. See also LEON TROTSKY CORRESPONDENCE/Harvard University; and NATALIA SEDOVA TROTSKAIA FILE/Correspondence/Harvard University
      - General. Memoranda, lists of material, and deeds of sale, Includes memoranda on sale of archives to Internationaal Instituut voor Sociale Geschiedenis, 1935; deeds of sale of archives to Harvard University, 1940 and 1953; and memoranda on access status, 1935-1980. (Folder 8)
      - Correspondence. Includes letters by Albert Goldman, Sara Weber, and officials of Harvard University and of the New York Public Library, 1939-1963 (Folder 9)
    - Assassination. Includes material on Ramon Mercader and David Alfaro Siqueiros. See also NEW YORK/COYOACAN FILE/ /General/Assassination, 1940
      - Clippings. Includes articles from The Chicago Daily News, Ercilla, Excelsior, France Observateur, The New York Daily News, The New York Herald-Tribune, The New York Post, The New York Times, The New York World-Telegram and Sun, and The Times (London), 1940-1978 (Folder 10)
      - Miscellany. Broadside by Partido Obrero Internacionalista (Mexico), 1940; photocopy of police fingerprints of Ramon Mercader; printed copy of United States. Congress. House. Committee on Un-American Activities report, American Aspects of Assassination of Leon Trotsky,; press release, 1959; and notes, 1951 (Folder 11)
      - Printed articles
        - 1940-1953. Includes series of articles by General Leandro A. Sanchez Salazar and Julian Gorkin in Revista de America, 1948; and articles in Life, Male, The New Leader, News Chronicle (London), Il Popolo d'Italia, Readers' Digest, La Stampa, True, and True Detective (Box 32, Folder 1)
        - 1954-1978. Includes printed excerpts from memoirs of Pablo Neruda, 1977; article by Bernard Wolfe in Coronet, 1959; and articles in Ahora!, I Grandi Fatti, Historia ilustrada, Maclean's, Magazine de policia, Manana, Le Nouvel Observateur, The Saturday Evening Post, Triunfo, and U.S. News and World Report (Folder 2)
    - Bibliography
      - Bibliographies prepared by the Lanka Samasamaja Party (Ceylon), and by the Socialist Workers Party, 1953-1956. (Folder 3)
      - Bibliography prepared by Pathfinder Press. Also includes miscellaneous bibliographical notes, 1979. (Folder 4)
    - Collected works. Correspondence of editors of Pathfinder Press with former associates of Leon Trotsky and veterans of the early Trotskyist movement, in connection with preparation of the Pathfinder Press editions of the collected works of Trotsky
      - Archer, John, 1976-1978 (Folder 5)
      - Curtiss, Charles, 1973 (Folder 6)
      - Frank, Pierre, 1968-1977 (Folder 7)
      - Groves, Reginald, 1973 (Folder 8)
      - Mandel, Ernest, 1973-1975 (Folder 9)
      - Naville, Pierre, 1972-1973 (Folder 10)
      - Pablo, Michel, 1974 (Folder 11)
      - Pieterson, Herman, 1976-1978 (Folder 12)
      - Van Heijenoort, Jean, 1971-1975 (Folder 13)
      - Wicks, Harry, 1973-1975 (Folder 14)
    - Estate. Certificate of legal agreement with the Mexican government, 1945 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Government surveillance
      - France. Photocopies of French police reports,; and printed copy of Annie Kriegel, "Le Dossier de Trotski a la Prefecture de Police de Paris," 1963, 1934 (Folder 2)
      - United States. Photocopy of register of United States Department of State and Department of Justice reports, 1929-1941 (Folder 3)
    - Interviews. Articles based on interviews with Leon Trotsky (not verbatim transcripts of interviews)
      - Politiken (Copenhagen), Typed copies (in Danish and English), 1929 June 22. (Folder 4)
      - Berliner Tageblatt, Printed copy (in English), 1930. (Folder 5)
      - Cumhuriyet (Istanbul), Printed copy (in Turkish), and typed copy (in English), 1932 December 12. (Folder 6)
      - Milliet (Istanbul), Printed copy (in Turkish), and typed copy (in English), 1932 December 12. (Folder 7)
      - Sun and Guardian Magazine (Sydney), Printed copy (in English), 1937 November 21. (Folder 8)
      - El Pais (Havana), Printed copy (in Spanish), 1938 November 14-18. (Folder 9)
      - Hoy (Mexico City), Printed copy (in Spanish), 1938 December 18. (Folder 10)
      - St. Louis Post-Dispatch, Printed copy (in English), 1940 March 10. (Folder 11)
    - Motion picture film. Letters and lists, Includes letter by Alexander Buchman, 1941-1945. (Folder 12)
    - Secretaries. List,; and notes on service of Joseph Hansen, 1975 (Folder 13)
    - Stalin. Letters, press releases, memoranda, and clipping, regarding controversies over the publishers' withdrawal of the book from publication in 1941, the content of the 1946 edition, and the introduction to the 1967 edition. Includes contract between Leon Trotsky and Harper and Brothers, 1938; typescript of introduction by Bertram D. Wolfe, 1967; printed excerpts from memoirs of Cass Canfield, 1972; and letters by Sylvia Bleecker, Morris D. Forkosch, Albert Goldman, Borys Lewytzky, Felix Morrow, Walter O'Rourke, Morris Stein, Esteban Volkov, John G. Wright, representatives of Curtis Brown Ltd., and Cass Canfield of Harper and Brothers, 1938-1972 (Folder 14)
  - Trotsky, Leon in fiction, drama, poetry, etc.
    - General. Clippings, 1960-1973 (Folder 15)
    - Mission to Moscow (Motion picture film: 1943). Letters, leaflets, press releases, clippings, lists, and printed article, 1943. Includes newspaper issue, The Truth about Mission to Moscow and the Moscow Trials; minutes of the Mission to Moscow Film Committee; and letters by Daniel Bell and Dwight Macdonald (Folder 16)
    - Trotzki im Exil (Play: Program, flyer, clippings, and biographical data on the playwright, Peter Weiss, 1970 (Folder 17)
    - The Assassination of Leon Trotsky (Motion picture film: 1972). Typescript of screenplay by Nicholas Mosley, and clippings, 1970-1972 (Folder 18)
    - Trotsky a Coyoacan (Play: Typescript of play script by Hartmut Lange (in French), n.d. (Folder 19)
- HARVARD UNIVERSITY SURVEY FILE, 1980 (Box 34-45)
  Survey sheets describing letters by Leon Trotsky (1929-1940) in the Exile Papers section of the Leon Trotsky Papers, Harvard University Library. Survey sheets were prepared by a Socialist Workers Party team of researchers upon the opening of the Exile Papers in 1980. They summarize contents of each letter, note existence of any published version, and, in some cases, include verbatim transcript or translation, and commentary. Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - Abern, Martin (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Action Socialiste Revolutionnaire (Folder 2)
  - Adelante (Folder 3)
  - Adler, Hans (Folder 4)
  - Adler, Jan (Folder 5)
  - Adler, Raisa (Folder 6)
  - Advokatenverein (Norway) (Folder 7)
  - Ageloff, Ruth (Folder 8)
  - Aggarwala, Hans Raj (Folder 9)
  - Alexander, Leon (Folder 10)
  - Allen, Henry (Folder 11)
  - America Libre (Folder 12)
  - American Committee for the Defense of Leon Trotsky (Folder 13)
  - Andrade, Juan (Folder 14)
  - Arlen (Folder 15)
  - Aubrin (Folder 16)
  - Auquier, Victor (Folder 17)
  - Austria. Konsulat (Istanbul) (Folder 18)
  - Balabanoff, Angelica (Folder 19)
  - Bardin, Alexis (Folder 20)
  - Bardin, Joannes (Folder 21)
  - Barton (Folder 22)
  - La Batalla (Folder 23)
  - Bauer, Eugen (Folder 24-25)
  - Beech, Dick (Folder 26)
  - Behens, Walter (Folder 27)
  - Belleville, Fritz (Folder 28)
  - Bennett, William (Folder 29)
  - Bergmann, Fritz (Folder 30)
  - Bergstrom, Evert (Folder 31)
  - Berl, Emmanuel (Folder 32)
  - Bermann (Folder 33)
  - Berndl, Ludwig (Folder 34)
  - Bernstein, Sidney (Folder 35)
  - Bill, Friedrich (Folder 36)
  - Biulleten' Oppozitsii (Folder 37)
  - Black, Samuel (Folder 38)
  - Bleiman, Junius (Folder 39)
  - Bocker, Sidney R. (Folder 40)
  - Boeglin (Folder 41)